Martin Skarzynski Laptev

Mission

My goal is to lead the next generation of scientists and engineers in building solutions that integrate substantive expertise from diverse fields with machine intelligence. Through my work, I strive to promote open source software, such as the Quarto publishing system, which I use to build dashboards, presentations, reports, websites, and other digital deliverables. Overall, I aim to leverage my broad scientific background and technical expertise to help transform the promises of science and technology into a better future for all of humanity.

Recent Experience

Lead Instructor, General Assembly

July 2019 - Present

- Teaches open-enrollment and enterprise courses such as:
 - Data Analytics
 Front-End Web Development
 - Python Programming
 React Development

Lead Instructor, Data Society

October 2019 - Present

- Provides enterprise clients with training in:
 - Machine Learning
 Natural Language Processing
 - R Programming
 Graph Analytics
 DevOps

Vice President, Data Community DC

April 2022 - Present

Leads a non-profit organization that supports <u>eleven Meetup groups</u>

Adjunct Professor, Virginia Tech

September 2021 - December 2023

Tech Excellence Data Science

Python Programming

- Taught two graduate courses for the Computer Science and Statistics Departments:
 - Machine Learning
- Data Analytics

Senior Domain Lead, Amazon Web Services

April 2022 - February 2023

- Provided customers with scientific and technical expertise in:
 - Computer Vision
- Data Architecture
- Data Visualization

Genomics

- Machine Learning
- Real World Evidence
- Built Artificial Intelligence (AI) solutions and Machine Learning Operations (MLOps) systems using:
 - Amazon SageMaker
- AWS Developer Tools
- AWS Lambda

- Amazon EventBridge
- AWS CloudFormation
- AWS IAM

Amazon EMR

- AWS Databases
- AWS Service Catalog

- Obtained 3 AWS certification
 - Solutions Architect Associate
- Cloud Practitioner
- Practical Data Science

AI Engineering Manager, Booz Allen Hamilton

October 2019 - March 2022

- Led a team of data scientists and software developers working on a cyber intelligence application
- Spearheaded interdisciplinary COVID-19 visualization, genomics, and statistical modeling efforts
- Obtained the Microsoft Azure Data Scientist Associate certification

Biomedical Scientist, National Institutes of Health

June 2009 - April 2021

- · Integrated clinical, laboratory, epidemiologic, genomic, and medical imaging data
- Combined deep learning and statistical inference using stacked ensembles
- Conducted genomic analysis of immune and cancer cells
- Developed and tested pharmaceutical and immunotherapeutic agents
- · Quantified cancer cell signaling pathways
- Mentored trainees from various NIH training programs including:

o SIF

o MRSP

HISTEP

Bioinformatics and Data Science Co-Chair, FAES

January 2014 - May 2020

- · Co-administered an academic program with over twenty faculty members
- Taught three graduate data science courses:
 - Introduction to Python
- Introduction to Text Mining
- Applied Machine Learning
- Taught graduate biotechnology workshops on various topics including:
 - Pharmacometrics
- Cellular Immunology
- Flow Cytometry

Adjunct Professor, George Washington University

January 2015 - May 2015

11-----

• Taught two undergraduate courses for the Women's Leadership Program:

- Describeration of a deep learning model [] to inform lung concer coroning intervals

- Biology of Organisms
- Women and Leadership

Education

MPH, Epidemiology and Biostatistics	May 2018
PhD, Tumor Biology	May 2015
MS, Biotechnology	June 2009
BA, Biology	May 2007

Select Publications

• <u>K</u>	ecalibration of a deep learning model [] to inform lung cancer screening intervals	March 2023
• <u>S/</u>	ARS-CoV-2 genome-based severity predictions correspond to [] higher viral load	May 2022
• <u>Li</u>	nking genotype to phenotype [] in SARS-CoV-2 []	April 2022
• <u>V</u> a	riants in SARS-CoV-2 associated with mild or severe outcome	June 2021
• <u>U</u>	sing prediction models to reduce [] disparities in [] lung cancer screening []	January 2021
• <u>Pa</u>	thogenic role of [BCR] signaling and canonical NF-κB activation in [MCL]	July 2016
• <u>In</u>	teractions between ibrutinib and anti-CD20 antibodies []	January 2016
• <u>H</u>	ealth disparities in the immunoprevention of [HPV] [] associated malignancies	December 2015
• <u>D</u>	esigning the furin-cleavable linker in recombinant immunotoxins []	May 2015
• <u>H</u>	arnessing the Fcµ receptor for [] therapy of [CLL]	October 2014

Select Awards

 Community Contribution of the Year Category Finalist, AWS Builder Awards 	February 2023
Artificial Intelligence Solutions Architect Award, BAH Emergent Skills Program	January 2022

Natural Languages

English: Native
 Russian: Professional
 Polish: Native
 Spanish: Professional
 French: Working
 Portuguese: Limited